Sometimes perfect strangers make the best friends.
Mary and Max is a animation, comedy, drama film directed by Adam Elliot.
A tale of friendship between two unlikely pen pals: Mary, a lonely, eight-year-old girl living in the
suburbs of Melbourne, and Max, a forty-four-year old, severely obese man living in New York.
Mary (voice), played by Toni Collette.
Max (voice), played by Philip Seymour Hoffman.
Narrator (voice), played by Barry Humphries.
Damien (voice), played by Eric Bana.
Young Mary (voice), played by Bethany Whitmore.
Vera Lorraine Dinkle (voice), played by Renée Geyer.
Mary and Max is a 2009 Australian stop-motion animated tragicomedy film written and
directed by Adam Elliot and was his first animated feature film.
The film was produced by Melanie Coombs and Melodrama
Pictures with music by Dale Cornelius.
The voice cast includes Philip Seymour Hoffman, Toni Collette, Eric Bana and
Bethany Whitmore, with narration provided by Barry Humphries.
The film follows the lives and friendship of two unlikely pen-pals; Mary, a lonely
Australian girl, and Max, a middle-aged American man with Asperger syndrome.
The film is inspired by Elliot's relationship with his "pen-friend" in New
York whom he has been writing to for over twenty years.
The film premiered on the opening night of the 2009
Sundance Film Festival on 15 January 2009.
The film won the Annecy Cristal in June 2009 from the Annecy International Animated Film Festival
and Best Animated Feature Film at the Asia Pacific Screen Awards in November 2009.
The film was also nominated for both the AACTA Award for Best Film and the
AACTA Award for Best Original Screenplay in December 2009.
The film was theatrically released on 9 April 2009, by Icon
Entertainment International; it received acclaim from critics.
The film explores themes of australia, chocolate, approach, letter, birthmark.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.